caltesting.org 2013-03-18

# Computerized Assessments & Learning - Contact Information

INFORMATION REGARDING THE POLICIES AND PROCEDURES OF COMPUTERIZED ASSESSMENTS AND LEARNING, LLC IN ITS COLLECTION, PROTECTION, USE AND DISCLOSURE OF CERTAIN PERSONAL INFORMATION GATHERED FROM STUDENTS IS SET FORTH IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY. IF YOU ARE A STUDENT UNDER THE AGE OF 18, PLEASE REVIEW THIS POLICY STATEMENT WITH YOUR PARENT OR GUARDIAN. IF YOU HAVE ANY CONCERNS REGARDING THE POTENTIAL DISSEMINATION OF YOUR ASSESSMENT RESULTS BY YOUR EDUCATIONAL INSTITUTION, PLEASE CONSULT THE PRIVACY POLICIES OF SUCH INSTITUTION. 

**Our commitment to privacy**

Computerized Assessments and Learning, LLC (CA&L) takes your privacy seriously. We are committed to protecting the privacy of personally identifiable information sent to us by students, administrators and educational institutions. It remains our policy and our commitment not to distribute, sell, rent or in any way make available any student’s name, email address or other personal information to any third party without such student’s prior written consent. 

**What information CA &L might collect**

CA&L provides online formative, interim, and summative testing for assessment by various educational institutions. Certain information is collected in this process from the student participating in the testing process, the account administrator administering the test(s), and the educational institution participating in this process. Set forth below is a description of the information that may be collected by CA&L in connection with CA&L’s services:

  * _**Students**_ : A student participating in any testing or assessment program will be required to access the testing materials online _._ Student information collected in connection with the testing process typically includes the following: 

  * Name 
  * Student Identification number 
  * Student demographic information 
  * Student Test Scores 
  * System Access Information 
  * IP Address of computers used for testing 

  * _**Administrators**_ : Information collected from administrators monitoring the testing program typically includes the following:

  * Name 
  * Administrator Identification number 
  * Work mail address 
  * Work phone number 
  * Email Address 
  * System Access Information 
  * IP Address of computers used to administer the assessments 

  * _**Educational Institutions**_ : Information collected from educational institutions typically includes:

  * Name 
  * ID Number 
  * Contact Information (Contact Name, Address, Phone number, Email, Fax) 
  * Employee list (system users must be associated with an educational institution) 
  * Student list 

**How CA &L uses the information**

  * _**Students:**_ Student information and test results from online testing will only be available to authorized administrators, teachers and, in approved cases, students. Students do not have access to each other’s online test results. Student passwords cannot be viewed by entities not approved via the educational institution. 

  * _**Administrators:**_ Students taking tests may be asked to submit personal information to the test administrator, such as name and other pertinent information (as described above) the CA&L account administrator requests. CA&L will not supply this information to any other third party, except as stated in this policy, although this information is available to the account administrator. CA&L is not responsible for the information a student may provide to the administrator. Students should contact the account administrator providing them access to the testing platform to ask about information the administrator may require, and the use of such information, before giving any such information.

  * _**Educational Institutions:**_ The educational institution and state agencies requesting the testing and assessment shall be provided with the testing results for each student. Information will be disseminated to educational institutions for evaluation of test status and results; data will not be shared with any entity that is not part of a contract without approval of the educational institution and state agencies. STUDENTS SHOULD CONTACT THEIR EDUCATIONAL INSTITUTION WITH REGARD TO ANY CONCERNS SUCH STUDENT MAY HAVE REGARDING HIS OR HER ASSESSMENT RESULTS, AND THE POTENTIAL DISCLOSURE OF SUCH ASSESSMENT RESULTS BY THE EDUCATIONAL INSTITUTION. CA&L IS IN NO WAY RESPONSIBLE FOR THE DISSEMINATION OF ASSESSMENT RESULTS BY ANY SUCH EDUCATIONAL INSTITUTION. 

**CA &L disclosure of information**

CA&L shall not knowingly sell, lend, or disclose to third parties any information collected from students, administrators and educational institutions, except as disclosed in this Privacy Policy or in the event CA&L is required by law to do so. CA&L may disclose information to its employees, consultants and agents who have a legitimate need to know the information for the purpose of providing quality service to our customers, and monitoring and improving the security of our network. CA&L reserves the right to disclose this information when special circumstances call for it, such as when disclosure is required by law or court order or when disclosure is, in our sole discretion, necessary to protect our legal rights, including intellectual property rights. 

**Protection**

CA&L servers are hosted in a high security data center which is staffed 24/7 and monitored by surveillance cameras. All equipment is securely locked and only authorized personnel have access. The data center has completed a SAS 70 audit. All logins and registrations are communicated via HTTPS, protected by an SSL certificate with a 2048 bit key. All data is completely private to the account administrator and is protected by secure servers. 

**Links**

The CA&L website may contain links to other websites. CA&L does not control the privacy policies or practices of these websites, and therefore users should review those policies before providing any information to a website linked from the CA&L site. CA&L is not responsible for the content or practices of any linked websites, and CA&L provides these links solely for the convenience and information of our visitors. 

**Acceptance of Terms**

CA&L is committed to protecting the privacy of all students, administrators and educational institutions utilizing CA&L’s assessment tools. By using the CA&L website, services, and applications, the user consents to the collection and use of the information provided in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

**General**

CA&L may amend this policy from time to time. If such amendments affect how CA&L uses or discloses personal information already hosted by CA&L in a material way, CA&L will obtain consent. New versions will be posted on the CA&L web site; users should check periodically for updates.

Queries regarding the CA&L privacy policy may be sent directly to CA&L:   
1202 East 23rd Street, Suite D  
Lawrence, KS 66046  
785-856-3850  
_[http://www.caltesting.org/](http://www.caltesting.org/)_
